<resources>
    <string name="app_name">AstroNerd</string>
    <string name="diameter_range">%.2f…%.2f</string>
    <string name="details_table_item_dangerous">Dangerous</string>
    <string name="details_table_item_min_diameter">Min diameter</string>
    <string name="details_table_item_max_diameter">Max diameter</string>
    <string name="details_table_item_close_approach">Close approach</string>
    <string name="details_table_item_relative_velocity">Relative velocity</string>
    <string name="details_table_item_miss_distance">Miss distance</string>
    <string name="details_table_item_orbiting_body">Orbiting body</string>
    <string name="details_table_item_is_sentry_object">Is sentry object</string>
    <string name="yes">Yes</string>
    <string name="no">No</string>
    <string name="details_chip_sbd">Go to SBD</string>
    <string name="details_switch_title_size">Size</string>
    <string name="details_switch_title_distance">Distance</string>
    <string name="details_chart_title_astronomical_distance">Astronomical distance</string>
    <string name="unit_astronomical">AU</string>
    <string name="toast_details_compare_error">You need at least 2 asteroids</string>
    <string name="notification_title_compare_error">So far, there is nothing to compare this asteroid with</string>
    <string name="point_your_phone_down">Point your phone down at an empty space, and move it around slowly</string>
    <string name="tap_anywhere_to_add_model">Tap anywhere to add model</string>


   <!-- Region facts-->
    <string name="title_sun">Sun</string>
    <string name="subtitle_sun">YELLOW DWARF STAR</string>
    <string name="body_sun">The Sun—the heart of our solar system—is a yellow dwarf star, a hot ball of glowing gases.\nIts gravity holds the solar system together, keeping everything from the biggest planets to the smallest particles of debris in its orbit. Electric currents in the Sun generate a magnetic field that is carried out through the solar system by the solar wind—a stream of electrically charged gas blowing outward from the Sun in all directions.\nThe connection and interactions between the Sun and Earth drive the seasons, ocean currents, weather, climate, radiation belts and aurorae. Though it is special to us, there are billions of stars like our Sun scattered across the Milky Way galaxy. The Sun, and everything that orbits it, is located in the Milky Way galaxy. More specifically, our Sun is in a spiral arm called the Orion Spur that extends outward from the Sagittarius arm. From there, the Sun orbits the center of the Milky Way Galaxy, bringing the planets, asteroids, comets and other objects along with it. Our solar system is moving with an average velocity of 450,000 miles per hour (720,000 kilometers per hour). But even at this speed, it takes us about 230 million years to make one complete orbit around the Milky Way.\nThe Sun rotates as it orbits the center of the Milky Way. Its spin has an axial tilt of 7.25 degrees with respect to the plane of the planets’ orbits. Since the Sun is not a solid body, different parts of the Sun rotate at different rates. At the equator, the Sun spins around once about every 25 days, but at its poles the Sun rotates once on its axis every 36 Earth days.</string>

    <string name="title_mercury">Mercury</string>
    <string name="subtitle_mercury">TERRESTRIAL</string>
    <string name="body_mercury">The smallest planet in our solar system and nearest to the Sun, Mercury is only slightly larger than Earth\'s Moon.\nMercury\'s surface temperatures are both extremely hot and cold. Because the planet is so close to the Sun, day temperatures can reach highs of 800°F (430°C). Without an atmosphere to retain that heat at night, temperatures can dip as low as -290°F (-180°C). From the surface of Mercury, the Sun would appear more than three times as large as it does when viewed from Earth, and the sunlight would be as much as seven times brighter. Despite its proximity to the Sun, Mercury is not the hottest planet in our solar system – that title belongs to nearby Venus, thanks to its dense atmosphere. But Mercury is the fastest planet, zipping around the Sun every 88 Earth days. Mercury\'s surface resembles that of Earth\'s moon, scarred by many impact craters resulting from collisions with meteoroids and comets. The first spacecraft to visit Mercury was Mariner 10, which imaged about 45 percent of the surface.NASA\'s MErcury Surface, Space ENvironment, GEochemistry, and Ranging (MESSENGER) mission flew by Mercury three times in 2008-2009 and orbited the planet from 2011 to 2015, mapping the entire surface.</string>

    <string name="title_venus">Venus</string>
    <string name="subtitle_venus">TERRESTRIAL</string>
    <string name="body_venus">Similar in size and structure to Earth, Venus has been called Earth\'s twin. These are not identical twins, however – there are radical differences between the two worlds.\nVenus and Earth are similar in size, mass, density, composition, and gravity. There, however, the similarities end. Venus has a thick, toxic atmosphere filled with carbon dioxide and it\’s perpetually shrouded in thick, yellowish clouds of mostly sulfuric acid that trap heat, causing a runaway greenhouse effect. It\’s the hottest planet in our solar system, even though Mercury is closer to the Sun. Venus has crushing air pressure at its surface – more than 90 times that of Earth – similar to the pressure you\'d encounter a mile below the ocean on Earth. Venus was the first planet to be explored by a spacecraft – NASA’s Mariner 2 successfully flew by and scanned the cloud-covered world on Dec. 14, 1962. Since then, numerous spacecraft from the U.S. and other space agencies have explored Venus, including NASA\’s Magellan, which mapped the planet\'s surface with radar. The former Soviet Union is the only nation to land on the surface of Venus to date, though the spacecraft did not survive long in the harsh environment.</string>

    <string name="title_earth">Earth</string>
    <string name="subtitle_earth">TERRESTRIAL</string>
    <string name="body_earth">With an equatorial diameter of 7926 miles (12,760 kilometers), Earth is the biggest of the terrestrial planets and the fifth largest planet in our solar system.\nFrom an average distance of 93 million miles (150 million kilometers), Earth is exactly one astronomical unit away from the Sun because one astronomical unit (abbreviated as AU), is the distance from the Sun to Earth. This unit provides an easy way to quickly compare planets\' distances from the Sun.\nAs Earth orbits the Sun, it completes one rotation every 23.9 hours. It takes 365.25 days to complete one trip around the Sun. That extra quarter of a day presents a challenge to our calendar system, which counts one year as 365 days. To keep our yearly calendars consistent with our orbit around the Sun, every four years we add one day. That day is called a leap day, and the year it\'s added to is called a leap year.\nEarth\'s axis of rotation is tilted 23.4 degrees with respect to the plane of Earth\'s orbit around the Sun. This tilt causes our yearly cycle of seasons. During part of the year, the northern hemisphere is tilted toward the Sun, and the southern hemisphere is tilted away. With the Sun higher in the sky, solar heating is greater in the north producing summer there. Less direct solar heating produces winter in the south. Six months later, the situation is reversed. When spring and fall begin, both hemispheres receive roughly equal amounts of heat from the Sun.</string>

    <string name="title_mars">Mars</string>
    <string name="subtitle_mars">TERRESTRIAL</string>
    <string name="body_mars">With a radius of 2,106 miles (3,390 kilometers), Mars is about half the size of Earth. If Earth were the size of a nickel, Mars would be about as big as a raspberry.\nFrom an average distance of 142 million miles (228 million kilometers), Mars is 1.5 astronomical units away from the Sun. One astronomical unit (abbreviated as AU), is the distance from the Sun to Earth. From this distance, it takes sunlight 13 minutes to travel from the Sun to Mars.\nAs Mars orbits the Sun, it completes one rotation every 24.6 hours, which is very similar to one day on Earth (23.9 hours). Martian days are called sols – short for "solar day." A year on Mars lasts 669.6 sols, which is the same as 687 Earth days.\nMars\' axis of rotation is tilted 25 degrees with respect to the plane of its orbit around the Sun. This is another similarity with Earth, which has an axial tilt of 23.4 degrees. Like Earth, Mars has distinct seasons, but they last longer than seasons here on Earth since Mars takes longer to orbit the Sun (because it\'s farther away). And while here on Earth the seasons are evenly spread over the year, lasting 3 months (or one quarter of a year), on Mars the seasons vary in length because of Mars\' elliptical, egg-shaped orbit around the Sun.\nSpring in the northern hemisphere (autumn in the southern) is the longest season at 194 sols. Autumn in the northern hemisphere (spring in the southern) is the shortest at 142 days. Northern winter/southern summer is 154 sols, and northern summer/southern winter is 178 sols.</string>

    <string name="title_jupiter">Jupiter</string>
    <string name="subtitle_jupiter">GAS GIANT</string>
    <string name="body_jupiter">With a radius of 43,440.7 miles (69,911 kilometers), Jupiter is 11 times wider than Earth. If Earth were the size of a grape, Jupiter would be about as big as a basketball.\nFrom an average distance of 484 million miles (778 million kilometers), Jupiter is 5.2 astronomical units away from the Sun. One astronomical unit (abbreviated as AU), is the distance from the Sun to Earth. From this distance, it takes sunlight 43 minutes to travel from the Sun to Jupiter.\nJupiter has the shortest day in the solar system. One day on Jupiter takes only about 10 hours (the time it takes for Jupiter to rotate or spin around once), and Jupiter makes a complete orbit around the Sun (a year in Jovian time) in about 12 Earth years (4,333 Earth days).\nIts equator is tilted with respect to its orbital path around the Sun by just 3 degrees. This means Jupiter spins nearly upright and does not have seasons as extreme as other planets do.</string>

    <string name="title_saturn">Saturn</string>
    <string name="subtitle_saturn">GAS GIANT</string>
    <string name="body_saturn">Saturn is the sixth planet from the Sun and the second largest planet in our solar system. Adorned with thousands of beautiful ringlets, Saturn is unique among the planets. It is not the only planet to have rings—made of chunks of ice and rock—but none are as spectacular or as complicated as Saturn\'s. Like fellow gas giant Jupiter, Saturn is a massive ball made mostly of hydrogen and helium.\nSurrounded by more than 140 known moons, Saturn is home to some of the most fascinating landscapes in our solar system. From the jets of water that spray from Enceladus to the methane lakes on smoggy Titan, the Saturn system is a rich source of scientific discovery and still holds many mysteries.The farthest planet from Earth discovered by the unaided human eye, Saturn has been known since ancient times. The planet is named for the Roman god of agriculture and wealth, who was also the father of Jupiter. Saturn\'s rings are thought to be pieces of comets, asteroids or shattered moons that broke up before they reached the planet, torn apart by Saturn\'s powerful gravity. They are made of billions of small chunksof ice and rock coated with another material such as dust. The ring particles mostly range from tiny, dust-sized icy grains to chunks as big as a house. A few particles are as large as mountains. The rings would look mostly white if you looked at them from the cloud tops of Saturn, and interestingly, each ring orbits at a different speed around the planet.</string>

    <string name="title_uranus">Uranus</string>
    <string name="subtitle_uranus">ICE GIANT</string>
    <string name="body_uranus">The seventh planet from the Sun with the third largest diameter in our solar system, Uranus is very cold and windy.\nThe ice giant is surrounded by 13 faint rings and 27 small moons as it rotates at a nearly 90-degree angle from the plane of its orbit. This unique tilt makes Uranus appear to spin on its side, orbiting the Sun like a rolling ball. Uranus is the only planet whose equator is nearly at a right angle to its orbit, with a tilt of 97.77 degrees—possibly the result of a collision with an Earth-sized object long ago. This unique tilt causes the most extreme seasons in the solar system. For nearly a quarter of each Uranian year, the Sun shines directly over each pole, plunging the other half of the planet into a 21-year-long, dark winter.\nUranus is also one of just two planets that rotate in the opposite direction than most of the planets (Venus is the other one), from east to west.</string>

    <string name="title_neptune">Neptune</string>
    <string name="subtitle_neptune">ICE GIANT</string>
    <string name="body_neptune">Dark, cold and whipped by supersonic winds, ice giant Neptune is the eighth and most distant planet in our solar system.\nMore than 30 times as far from the Sun as Earth, Neptune is the only planet in our solar system not visible to the naked eye. In 2011 Neptune completed its first 165-year orbit since its discovery in 1846.\nNeptune is so far from the Sun that high noon on the big blue planet would seem like dim twilight to us. The warm light we see here on our home planet is roughly 900 times as bright as sunlight on Neptune. Neptune is one of two ice giants in the outer solar system (the other is Uranus). Most (80 percent or more) of the planet\'s mass is made up of a hot dense fluid of "icy" materials — water, methane and ammonia — above a small, rocky core. Of the giant planets, Neptune is the densest.\nScientists think there might be an ocean of super hot water under Neptune\'s cold clouds. It does not boil away because incredibly high pressure keeps it locked inside. Neptune\'s atmosphere is made up mostly of hydrogen and helium with just a little bit of methane. Neptune\'s neighbor Uranus is a blue-green color due to such atmospheric methane, but Neptune is a more vivid, brighter blue, so there must be an unknown component that causes the more intense color.</string>

</resources>